Guide to the Divinity Student Council Records, 2011-2015 and undated UA.31.02.0006
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Divinity Student Council records
2011-2015 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Duke University. Divinity Student Council
UA.31.02.0006
0.4 Linear Feet
The Divinity Student Council (DSC) is a student organization within the Divinity School that coordinates and assists students and other student organizations within the school by approving the creation or affiliation of groups as official DSC student gourps, assisting in the planning and communication of events and activities, representing the needs and concerns of the student body to the administration of the Divinity School, discovering and responding to the needs of the student body, and collecting dues and other monies for these purposes. The Divinity Student Council Records consist of materials related to the functions of the Divinity School Council, especially in the planning of events and activities, the election of representatives, and its work with affiliated groups.
Related Materials
Graduate and Professional Student Council Records, Duke University Archives, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University.
Student Organizations Reference Collection, Duke University Archives, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University.
Divinity School Reference Collection, Duke University Archives, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University.
Divinity School Records, Duke University Archives, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University.
Office of Student Activities and Facilities Records, Duke University Archives, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University.
Historical note
The Divinity Student Council (DSC) is a student organization within the Divinity School that coordinates and assists students and other student organizations within the school by approving the creation or affiliation of groups as official DSC student gourps, assisting in the planning and communication of events and activities, representing the needs and concerns of the student body to the administration of the Divinity School, discovering and responding to the needs of the student body, and collecting dues and other monies for these purposes. The DSC is made up of elected student representatives and operates committees, including the Executive Board Committee and Finance Committee. Representatives include co-presidents, a treasurer and secretary, class representatives, and representatives to larger student organizations, including the Graduate and Professional Student Council.
Collection Overview
The Divinity Student Council Records consist of materials related to the functions of the Divinity School Council, especially in the planning of events and activities, the election of representatives, and its work with affiliated groups. Materials include meeting minutes, forms, policies, fliers, newsletters, and lists of resources for elected representatives. Materials related to the Refectory, the Black Seminarian's Union, and the DSC Executive Committee are restricted for ten years from date of creation.
Provenance
The Divinity Student Council Records were received by the University Archives as a transfer in February, 2015.
Access Restrictions
Files related to The Refectory, Black Seminarians Union, and DSC Executive Committee are restricted for 10 years from the date of their creation by request of the Divinity Student Council. Access permission may be granted in writing by the current DSC president. Other materials are open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48-hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Seminarians; Duke University. Divinity Student Council; Duke University. Divinity School -- Students; Duke University. Graduate and Professional Student Council; Duke University -- Students -- Societies, etc; Duke University. Divinity Student Council
- Divinity Student Council records
  - Administrative materials, 201-2013 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Affiliated student groups, 2011-2015 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - DSC General Body meeting minutes, 2011-2014 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - DSC News, 2012-2013 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Elections to DSC, 2013 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Flyers and postings, 2012-2013, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Friendship House, 2012 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Leadership transition resources, 2011-2013 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Lenten prayer guide, 2011 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - 2012-2013 Planning retreat (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Student orientation, 2012-2013 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - The Refectory, circa 2012 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Access Restrictions
    Access restricted until 2022.
  - Black Seminarians Union, 2011 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Access restricted until 2021.
  - DSC Executive Committee, 2011-2013 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Access restricted until 2023.